<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Computer Repair Doctor</title>
	<atom:link href="https://computerrepairdoctor.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/</link>
	<description>iPhone Repair, Computer Repair, Laptop Repair</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 13:53:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/cropped-A_tighter_3-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Computer Repair Doctor</title>
	<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>6 of 2022’s Top All-in-One PCs</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/6-of-2022s-top-all-in-one-pcs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 13:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=20268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All-in-one PCs are now getting wide that’s fitting for high-professional use or a basic desktop for kid’s classes and homework. It takes up less room than traditional towers that can feel cramping; offers more screen space that’s larger than the largest laptops.&#160; These systems pack their components, ports, and monitors into a single unit that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>All-in-one PCs are now getting wide that’s fitting for high-professional use or a basic desktop for kid’s classes and homework. It takes up less room than traditional towers that can feel cramping; offers more screen space that’s larger than the largest laptops.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These systems pack their components, ports, and monitors into a single unit that allows you to easily place them in your workplace. But because it’s compacted in a single unit, you can’t crack it open to fix or swap the components freely. So here are the top all-in-one desktops to help you in choosing.</p>



<ol><li>HP Pavilion 24 All-in-One</li></ol>



<p>This has a 3GHz speed six-core AMD Ryzen 5 4600H processor with 16GB RAM, 256GB SSD boot drive, and 1TB hard drive as a secondary drive. This operates with Windows 10 Home with AMD Radeon graphics displayed on a 23.8 inches screen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The IPS touch screen offers full HD 1920&#215;1080 native resolution. This also has a high-resolution 5-megapixel webcam with a pop-up privacy design and a quad-array digital microphone that’s already great for videoconferencing and online chat. HP Pavilion 24 all-in-one desktop already gives a potent performance for as low as $799.99 in direct-to-customer configuration.</p>



<p>It has a plain rectangular base and slim stand support with tilt but no height adjustment. This 14.8-pound computer doesn&#8217;t swivel but it’s not difficult to move.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The desktop has a headphone jack and one USB Type-A port on the right edge of the display; the power button is at the bottom left; three more USB-A ports and one Type-C port at the rear; along with an SD slot; a Gigabit Ethernet jack; HDMI-out port to connect a second display; HDMI-in to connect a cable box or game console to the screen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The USB ports follow the USB 3.1Gbps spec. This Pavilion 24 has Bluetooth and 802.11ac Wi-Fi to handle wireless communications and a laptop-style 120-watt power brick plugs into the rear. The Pavilion comes with a color-coordinated white keyboard and a mouse that takes two of the rear USB ports.</p>



<ol start="2"><li>Asus M241&nbsp;</li></ol>



<p>Asus M241 has a 2.6GHz speed AMD Ryzen 3 3250U CPU with 8GB RAM, and 256GB SSD boot drive. This operates with Windows 10 Home with AMD Radeon Vega 3 graphics displaying on a 23.8 inches screen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The non-touchscreen offers full HD 1920&#215;1080 native resolution.</p>



<p>This features a metal, L-shaped stand that looks familiar to the iMac&#8217;s base. M241’s speaker bar is 0.9 inches thick; the base and speaker bar are muted gold in color. The display is bordered by 0.2-inch thick bezels that give a sleek look. All but two of its ports are placed in a row in the center of the back panel.</p>



<ol start="3"><li>Apple iMac 24-Inch</li></ol>



<p>This has an Apple M1 processor with 16GB RAM, and a 512GB SSD boot drive. This operates with MacOS Big Sur with Apple M1 graphics. This non-touchscreen type desktop has a 23.5 inches screen size of 0.44 inches thick with 4480&#215;2520 native resolution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This all-in-one PC is available in seven tones. The Magic Mouse, the Magic Keyboard, and Magic Trackpad (optional) have color-matched aluminum sides and surfaces. The iMac’s power cord and the USB-C-to-Lighting cable used to charge the wireless peripherals are made of woven and color-matched material. The stand offers tilt but not height adjustment. The power adapter is upgradeable with a gigabit Ethernet port built-in.</p>



<ol start="4"><li>HP Envy 34 All-in-One&nbsp;</li></ol>



<p>This has an Intel Core i7-11700 processor with 2.5GHz speed. This has a storage amount of 32GB RAM, and a 1TB SSD boot drive. This operates with Windows 11 Pro with Nvidia GeForce RTX 3060 Laptop GPU graphics. This 34 inches non-touchscreen desktop has a 5120&#215;2160 native resolution with an aspect ratio of 21:9. HP’s latest update of the Envy 34 which starts at $1,999.99 to $2,709.99 is one of the best AIOs.</p>



<p>It got a 5k display, a movable camera, and a snappy performance. It has a different USB webcam design. It&#8217;s magnetically detachable that allows moving at any edge of the system and also has above average camera quality of 16MP sensor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The connectivity option is more than the most. The system has more ports than many AIO offers. Most are located at the back of the monitor that includes four USB 3.0 ports, two USB Type-C ports with Thunderbolt 4 support, an HDMI connection, and an Ethernet jack. There are additional ports on the right-hand side of the stand that hold two more USB 3.0 ports, a USB-C connection, and an SD card slot. Envy 34 also comes with a basic Bluetooth mouse and keyboard.</p>



<ol start="5"><li>Apple iMac 27-Inch</li></ol>



<p>Apple iMac 27-inch ($1,799) has a 3.6GHz speed 10-core Intel Core i9-10910 brain. This has a storage amount of 32GB RAM, and a 1TB SSD boot drive. This 27 inches wide non-touchscreen desktop has a 5120&#215;2880 native resolution with a vastly better 1080p camera. This operates with Apple macOS Catalina with AMD Radeon Pro 5700 XT graphics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This iMac weighs 19.7 pounds and measures 20.3 inches in height, 25.6 inches in width, and 8 inches in dimension. This system includes four USB 3.0 Type-A ports, two oval-shaped USB Type-C ports with Thunderbolt 3 support, an Ethernet jack, a full-size SD card slot, a headphone jack, and a port for power adapter. The Ethernet port is now upgradeable to 10Gbps.</p>



<ol start="6"><li>HP Chromebase All-in-One 22</li></ol>



<p>HP Chromebase has an Intel Pentium Gold 6405U processor with a 2.4GHz speed. This has a storage amount of 4GB RAM, and a 64GB eMCC Flash Memory boot drive. This operates with Google Chrome OS with Intel UHD Graphics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This 21.5 inches touch screen type has 1920&#215;1080 native resolution and a modest 250-nit maximum brightness rating with a 5-megapixel webcam. This all-in-one desktop is different from others with a display that can rotate in landscape and portrait modes. This has a 6.7 inches in diameter cone-shaped base that doubles as a speaker.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are no height adjustments. The ports are located at the back of the base having the power button on the top, and a quartet of USB ports (Type-A and Type-C and USB-C ports) variety. This $479.99 desktop already includes a wireless keyboard and mouse.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Best Productivity Apps for iPhone Users</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/5-best-productivity-apps-for-iphone-users/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 12:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=20200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Making use of productivity apps makes it easier to set goals, assign tasks, track progress, and create reports. And this influences us to meet more productivity whether it’s for work, organizing a family vacation, or planning for an event. But productivity apps have different types, and you might not be using the best one for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>Making use of productivity apps makes it easier to set goals, assign tasks, track progress, and create reports. And this influences us to meet more productivity whether it’s for work, organizing a family vacation, or planning for an event. But productivity apps have different types, and you might not be using the best one for you. So here are some productivity apps for iPhone users.</p>



<ol><li>Apple Notes</li></ol>



<p>This is the best note-taking app for iPhone users. Remember everything and tackle any project with your list, notes, tasks, and schedule all in one app. When you put your notes here, it automatically syncs to all your devices. This helps you work anywhere because it keeps important info handy.&nbsp; You can also add text, images, audio, scans, PDFs, maps, and documents that make your note more useful. Make your tasks easier to do with your notes with checklists and tap check-off items as you go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This app has powerful and flexible searching capabilities that help you to get what you need in a matter of seconds. You can also scan documents to make them handier and save web pages and mark them with arrows, highlights, and texts to make them more useful. Apple Note can secure notes containing sensitive or personal data with a password, keep your notes in folders and subfolders then sort them as you prefer, and create Custom Smart Folders based on one or more tags. You can share and collaborate on entire shared folders, mention friends to alert them to important updates and direct them to a shared note and view the edit times and dates for the note with highlighted text color-coded to match the collaborators who were involved in the creation of the note. Quick Notes can be created on compatible iPad and Mac systems and viewed and edited on iPhone.</p>



<ol start="2"><li>Outlook</li></ol>



<p>It has impressive utility and power features, making it the ideal alternative to the more popular Gmail. Outlook helps you protect and keep your inbox clutter-free working around the clock. You can add popular services like Dropbox, Trello, Grammarly, and more, making it an ideal way to keep your workflow in one place.</p>



<p>It also has a To-Do feature that was formerly called Wunderlist. It also has an Immersive Reading Mode that filters images and quotes out of your email to present it as a clear document and complete with text-to-voice capabilities. Collaboration is easy with Word, PowerPoint, and Excel. With Skype, you can chat in real-time, right from your inbox. It has a built-in Calendar to keep you on track with your tasks. Outlook allows Two-factor authentication and email encryption for security. Outlook is easy to use since it’s designed to be more accessible to everyone with intuitive voice-control navigation, and support for multiple assistive devices.&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="3"><li>2Do</li></ol>



<p>2Do was designed to meet your speed needs. You can quickly enter your thoughts and ideas before forgetting. You can enter multiple tasks in seconds with Quick Add on iOS. Quick Entry on Mac, on the other hand, is a comprehensive task editor that can be accessed anywhere, anytime, even when 2Do is not running. It’s simplistic appearance but it houses an incredible productivity-aware engine that can be as fierce as your workflow. It offers the perfect mix of a rich feature set and ease of use. From a full set of sorting filters, focus, tags, location, and date range, it will surprise you in every way with the amount of thoughtfulness and attention to detail that went into developing it. 2Do gives you complete control over all your workflows giving you the freedom to organize your lists, categorize, and sort them. Your notes can sync into iCloud, Dropbox, and Toodledo.</p>



<ol start="4"><li>Apple Calendar</li></ol>



<p>Apple Calendar is a user-friendly app installed on all MacBooks, iPhones, iPads, and Apple Watches in several versions of macOS and iOS. Your account syncs across desktop and iPhone so you can manage your schedule wherever you are. It&#8217;s knowledgeable to use and has all the features you&#8217;d expect from a web-based calendar, including the ability to create multiple calendars and customize the view of each calendar so you can see your schedule by day, week, and month.</p>



<ol start="5"><li>Streaks</li></ol>



<p>This is a great habit-tracking app for iPhone. This has two excellent features that set it apart from the other habit-tracker apps. It integrates very well with Apple’s ecosystem including Mac and Apple Watch and can be seamlessly integrated with Apple’s Health app, and its robust charts and graphics give you a more detailed interpretation of habit-tracking. You can choose or create up to twelve tasks. Streaks can automatically track certain goals with the iOS Health app. You can set how many times in a day per week, in a month, or every day. This app lets you quickly see which tasks are remaining for the day, and what’s in progress, and marked as complete. You can view your task statistics to keep you motivated.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 3 Gaming Laptops of 2022</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/top-3-gaming-laptops-of-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 11:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=20122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you looking for a gaming laptop that will win you more games and help you stay productive? Check out this article for the year’s top three gaming laptops. Razer Blade 15 Razer Blade 15 got even better with a new top-level Razer Blade 15 Advance Model. This beastly performing gaming laptop is now compact [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>Are you looking for a gaming laptop that will win you more games and help you stay productive? Check out this article for the year’s top three gaming laptops.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Razer Blade 15</h2>



<p>Razer Blade 15 got even better with a new top-level Razer Blade 15 Advance Model. This beastly performing gaming laptop is now compact with the latest 12th Gen Intel Core i9 processor (14-core) and NVIDIA with graphics up to GeForce RTX 30 Series laptop GPUs, previously with 6-Core Intel Core i7 with graphics of GeForce RTX 3070 laptop GPU, giving you the most impressive gaming laptop graphics ever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Razer Blade 15 has an amazing display with Full HD 360Hz, QHD 240Hz (G-SYNC), or the new 4K with UHD 144Hz display. The already high-end former model that performs with Windows 10 Home is free to upgrade to operate with Windows 11 Home.</p>



<p>You can enjoy an unbeatable performance loaded in the thinnest 15” RTX gaming laptop chassis ever. It has spectacular specs loaded with a large amount of storage space of 1TB PCle and an extra M.2 PCle slot, memory of 16GB to 36GB RAM (DDR5 4800MHz), a vapor chamber cooling system, and a per-key RGB keyboard. This top-notch gaming laptop that is thinner from 0.78” / 19.9 mm to 0.67” / 16.99 mm also has an SD card reader port.</p>



<p>The latest Razer welcomes some other improvements. The keycaps are larger. Though it’s not that noticeable, it makes it easier to touch so that you can type quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The power button has been replaced by a less meticulous full-size key in the top right corner of the keyboard. It looks cleaner and more sensible. The new speakers also got sleeker. Razer’s touchpad remains one of the best in any Windows laptop with its smooth panning delivery, responsive presses, and high-quality feel. Last year&#8217;s model upgraded the webcam to 1080p, so you’ll get a better video call experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Razer Blade 15 Advanced model is still the most excessive among gaming laptops with a base configuration price of $2,499.99, but its CPU and GPU bring an incredible on-edge gaming experience with a high-quality portable design. It is also available on Amazon, Best Buy, B&amp;H, and Newegg.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Asus ROG Zephyrus G14 GA402 2022</h2>



<p>Asus has released its new ROG Zephyrus G14 GA402 with various models yet nearly similar to each other. These are consisting of RJ-L8106W, RJ-L8147W, RJ-L8146W, RJ-L8145W, RK-L8135W, RK-L8134W, RK-L8133W, and RK-L8132W.</p>



<p>ROG Zephyrus G14 GA402 operates with Windows 11 Home runs with AMD Ryzen 9 6900HS Mobile Processor (8-core/16-thread, 16MB cache, 4.9GHz max boost). All of the models have 8GB GDDR6 but the RJ models’ graphics have AMD Radeon RX 6700S ROG boost up to 100W(SmartShift), while the RK models have AMD Radeon RX 6800 ROG boost up to 105W(SmartShift). It has a $1,649 configuration for RX 6700 and $2,499 for RX 6800.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of its displays are the same as the ROG Nebula display, QHD+ 16:10 (2560 x 1600, WQXGA), an anti-glare display, a refresh rate of 120Hz, a response time of 3ms, and supports Dolby Vision HDR.</p>



<p>Its memory is available in either 8GB DDR5 or 16GB DDR5 on the board, 8GB DDR5 or 16GB DDR5 SO-DIMM, with a maximum capacity of either 24GB or 32GB, and can support dual-channel memory. This gaming laptop has a large storage space of 1TB PCle 4.0 NVMe M.2 SSD, all I/O ports that are needed are available, backlit chiclet keyboard 1-Zone RGB touchpad, and 720 HD IR camera for Windows Hello.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Its audio has some wonderful specs like a 4-speaker system with Smart Amplifier, a built-in 3-microphone array, and AI noise-canceling technology. You can have a great experience in its network and communication with Wi-Fi 6E(802.11ax) (Dual-band) plus Bluetooth 5.2 (may vary with OS upgrades). Its battery has 76WHrs, 4S1P, and 4-cell Li-ion. Can have AniMe Matrix that’s adding a customizable, dynamic LED grid to the laptop’s lid. It weighs from 1.65 Kg (3.64 lbs) to 1.75 Kg (3.79 lbs) with different dimensions too.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Razer Blade 14 AMD Ryzen 5900HX</h2>



<p>This Razer Blade 14 costs as much as $2,599.99. Pretty expensive, right? But it can also perform expensively. This device processor is AMD Ryzen 9 5900HX with 8 Cores / 16 Threads, a 3.3GHz base, and a 4.6GHz maximum boost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Updating its Windows is free if available. It has a display of 14-inch QHD 165Hz, 2560 x 1440, a graphics of NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3080 (8GB VRAM). Amazing graphic features like NVIDIA® GeForce RTX™ 3080 Laptop GPU, 8GB GDDR6 VRAM, NVIDIA CUDA® Cores &#8211; 6144, Maximum Graphics Power up to 100W, Boost Clock up to 1365MHz, NVIDIA GPU Boost™ 2.0, NVIDIA Optimus™ Technology, NVIDIA Whisper Mode 2.0, NVIDIA Resizable BAR, 2nd Gen Ray Tracing Cores, 3rd Gen Tensor Cores, and VR ready.</p>



<p>It has a storage of 1TB SSD, a memory of 16GB DDR4-3200MHz (fixed on the board), Wi-Fi 6E (802.11ax) and 5.2 Bluetooth connectivity, and a per-key RGB keyboard, Microsoft Precision Glass touchpad.&nbsp; It also has amazing audio of built-in stereo speakers and a 3.5mm headphones/microphone combo port.</p>



<p>It’s finished with CNC Aluminum, anodized black, and a backlit green Razer logo with the dimensions of 16.8mm x 220mm x 319.7mm that weighs 1.78 Kg (3.92lbs). It is amazing to have powerful hardware with such slimness like a pro. 1.78 Kg may be heavy, but for an NVIDIA RTX 3080? This is just impressive.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 4 iPhone accessories for 2022</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/top-4-iphone-accessories-for-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 12:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=20024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Having an iPhone may already be quintessential for some people, but others still want to have a next-level extra. There are accessories that can make the iPhone push more performance, more secure, and more useful like leveling up photos and videos or charging up the device. Prime Cables Lightning to HDMI Digital AV Adapter The [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>Having an iPhone may already be quintessential for some people, but others still want to have a next-level extra. There are accessories that can make the iPhone push more performance, more secure, and more useful like leveling up photos and videos or charging up the device.</p>



<ol><li>Prime Cables Lightning to HDMI Digital AV Adapter</li></ol>



<p>The Lightning Digital AV Adapter supports mirroring of whatever is displayed on the device screen. This includes apps, presentations, websites, slideshows, and more. This adapter can be used with iPhone, iPad, or iPod with a Lightning connector. This AV adapter can connect to HDMI-equipped TV, display, projector, or other compatible monitors in up to 1080p HD. This can enhance the versatility of entertainment systems or presentations. This HDMI adapter is fast and easy to use. This Lightning to HDMI adapter can connect to most HDMI displays that broaden the use of the devices. The displaying photos, videos or other presentations from the iPhone can already be shared with family, friends, students, and others. This Apple Lightning Digital AV Adapter made browsing on larger screens easier and better.&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="2"><li>Apple AirTag</li></ol>



<p>AirTags are used to help track important stuff such as keys, bags, wallets, purses, devices, and others. This lessens the possibility of losing things. This keeps things on the owner&#8217;s radar. This uses the Find My app which can also track Apple devices. This cute keychain-looking Apple AirTag can play sounds on the built-in speaker via the new Items tab in the Find My app. It has Bluetooth proximity finding, Apple designed U1 chip for Ultra-Wideband and Precision Finding that uses an accelerometer sensor and NFC tap for Lost Mode. This can lead straight to the lost item; it displays the distance to the AirTag and the direction to head in. The Precision Finding is compatible with iPhone 11/Pro/ProMax, iPhone 12/mini/Pro/Pro Max, and iPhone 13/mini/Pro/Pro Max.</p>



<p>The tag efficiently sends out a secure Bluetooth signal to nearby devices in the Find My Network. The location of the AirTag signal is sent to the iCloud; then to the Find My app and can be viewed on a map. The process is encrypted and anonymous to protect privacy. When Lost Mode is turned on and detected by other devices in the network, this automatically sends a notification. The contact info of the owner can be gotten by the NFC tap. AirTag is still designed to discourage unwanted tracking. Only the owner can see where his AirTag is. The location data and history are never stored on the tag itself. The devices that relay the location of the owner’s AirTag also stay anonymous.</p>



<p>Its battery life is designed with a user-replaceable CR2032 coin cell battery that can last more than a year, and iPhone gives a notification when it’s time to be replaced. The 31.9 mm x 8 mm tag that weighs lightly as 11g is also Rated IP67 resistant to splash, water, and dust. That is a maximum depth of 1 meter up to 30 meters under IEC standard 60529 that should have an operating ambient temperature of -20 ℃ to 60 ℃.</p>



<ol start="3"><li>Otterbox Amplify Glass Glare Guard</li></ol>



<p>The Amplify Glare Guard is a Corning Aluminosilicate glass screen protector that is available for iPhones 11/Pro Max, iPhone 13/Pro/mini/Pro Max, and iPhone XR. The anti-glare screen protector defends screens against drops, scratches, and scrapes up to 5x greater resistance than leading glass alternatives while giving improved display readability from low to extreme lighting. The 0.04 lbs glass protector also boasts a lowered screen-brightness setting that enables extended daily battery life. This comes with an installation frame, cleaning wipe, drying cloth, and dust removal sticker.</p>



<ol start="4"><li>Master &amp; Dynamic MC100 Wireless Charge Pad</li></ol>



<p>The Master &amp; Dynamic MC100 Wireless charge pad is built to complement the MW08 Sport True Wireless Earphones that can be used with the iPhone. It is a beautifully engineered wireless charger having a low-profile look that is available in colors silver aluminum with grey coated canvas and gunmetal aluminum with black coated canvas. This charging disk measures 100mm by 100mm and is 9.9mm thick and weighs 90.7g. This gives 10 Watts of maximum output with an input of 5v/1.2~1.5A, 9V/1.2~1.5A.</p>



<p>The charging pad does not include an AC wall adapter. It has a LED indicator on the front of the charger which looks like a round drink coaster. It illuminates when a device is charging without being too bright. The bottom side of the Master &amp; Dynamic MC100 Wireless Charge Pad is made from machined aluminum and has four anti-skid rubber feet to keep the MC100 from sliding around. Master &amp; Dynamic claims that this charging pad can charge the MW08 Sport to 50% in just 30 minutes and a full charge from empty will take up to 100 minutes.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>iPhone Battery Health: How to Check and Improve It</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/iphone-battery-health-how-to-check-and-improve-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 05:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=19791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just like all batteries, iPhone batteries tend to deteriorate in performance over time. An iPhone that can last you 12 hours out of the box can only last you two or three hours after a year or two. You wonder, why does my iPhone’s battery health deteriorate so fast? Well, the answer is because that’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>Just like all batteries, iPhone batteries tend to deteriorate in performance over time. An iPhone that can last you 12 hours out of the box can only last you two or three hours after a year or two. You wonder, why does my iPhone’s battery health deteriorate so fast?</p>



<p>Well, the answer is because that’s meant to happen. However, there are ways you can slow down this inevitable deterioration of your iPhone battery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Check Your iPhone’s Battery Health</h2>



<p>First, you might want to check your iPhone’s battery health percentage. Here’s how:</p>



<ol><li>Launch “Settings.”</li><li>Scroll down and find “Battery.”</li><li>Tap “Battery Health.”</li></ol>



<p>The “Maximum Capacity” is the maximum charge percentage your iPhone battery can reach relative to its health. When your battery is new, the number should be at 100%. You’ll notice that over time, the percentage goes down.</p>



<p>But if it goes down at an alarming rate, for example, at least 1 percent per week, you should take measures to prolong your battery’s lifespan. But if you’re a heavy user, you should expect this rate. Consistently using demanding apps, keeping your iPhone plugged in, and using it while charging deteriorates it.</p>



<p>That means the more time you fully discharge and charge your iPhone battery, the faster its “Battery Health” percentage goes down. Faster deterioration means you need to get an iPhone battery replacement service one or two years after getting a new iPhone.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Improve Your iPhone’s Battery Health</h2>



<p>If you want to slow down the fall, here are some practices you can apply to your daily smartphone routine:</p>



<ol><li>Don’t get the battery percentage down to 0%.</li></ol>



<p>0% battery is the time your iPhone shuts itself down in the middle of an activity because it’s out of juice. To save your iPhone’s battery from fast deterioration, avoid fully discharging it. Charge your battery when the percentage drops below 20%, the time when you get low battery warnings on your screen.</p>



<p>If you’re nowhere near a charging station, turn on “Low Power Mode” in “Settings” &gt; “Battery.”</p>



<ol start="2"><li>Don’t fully charge your battery all the time.</li></ol>



<p>It’s understandable to want to have a fully charged phone, but consistently charging your iPhone’s battery from 0% to 100% severely hurts its health. When you can, charge your iPhone up to 50% or a little more.</p>



<p>If you’re going out and won’t have the chance to charge again, take advantage of the iPhone’s “Low Power Mode.”</p>



<ol start="3"><li>Avoid storing or using your phone in high temperatures.</li></ol>



<p>If your iPhone starts to feel hot on your hands, it’s time to put it down and give it a rest. But when you do, make sure to store it in a dry, cool place to help it cool itself down and save its battery and other components from damage.</p>



<p>According to <a href="https://www.apple.com/ph/batteries/maximizing-performance/">Apple</a>, the iPhone works best in 0 to 35 degrees celsius environments. For storage, the iPhone can be comfortable at -20 to 45 degrees celsius.</p>



<p><strong>Note:</strong> When storing an iPhone long-term, make sure you turn it off with the battery percentage at 50%.</p>



<ol start="4"><li>Remove thick cases when charging your iPhone.</li></ol>



<p>If you’re a fan of thick iPhone cases because of the protection they offer, make sure to check how breathable they are. They might be too thick to the point that your iPhone can’t breathe and let heat out when it needs to, which happens during charging.</p>



<p>Check if the case is breathable. If not, remove it before plugging your iPhone in.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Parting Words</h2>



<p>Truthfully, you can’t save your iPhone’s battery from deterioration. They’re made to be used and are susceptible to wear, that’s why they’re easily replaceable through professional iPhone battery replacement services.</p>



<p>However, it’s still a good idea to try to reduce the speed of its deterioration. But when the time comes for your iPhone to get a fresh battery, remember to rely on the experts to help you out.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>iPhone 13 vs. Samsung Galaxy S22: Which One Should You Get?</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/iphone-13-vs-samsung-galaxy-s22-which-one-should-you-get/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 15:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=19678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With so many choices in the market, it’ll take a lot of time just to come down to a 1 versus 1 of the devices you’re going to choose from. However, iPhones usually take the other side of the fight for casual smartphone users. If you’re one of the people picking between the iPhone 13 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>With so many choices in the market, it’ll take a lot of time just to come down to a 1 versus 1 of the devices you’re going to choose from. However, iPhones usually take the other side of the fight for casual smartphone users. If you’re one of the people picking between the iPhone 13 and Samsung Galaxy S22 5G, this guide will help you decide.</p>



<p>We’ll break this guide down into four categories:</p>



<ul><li>Body</li><li>Display</li><li>Platform</li><li>Camera</li><li>Price</li></ul>



<p>You can skip through the categories you care most about to help yourself decide faster! But if you’re like us who like getting down to the nitty-gritty of gadgets we plan to spend our money on, read through our buying guide.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Body</h2>



<p><strong>iPhone 13:</strong> The iPhone 13 weighs 174 grams and is measured at 5.78 x 2.81 x 0.30 in. The front and back of its aluminum frame are powered by Gorilla Glass, which can be found on most smartphones today. The iPhone 13 is also IP68-rated dust- and water-resistant, and you can swim up to 6 meters deep for 30 mins with your iPhone 13 if you’re into that!</p>



<p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S22 5G: </strong>On the other side of the ring, the Samsung Galaxy S22 5G weighs 167 grams and is measured at 5.75 x 2.78 x 0.30 in. Similar to the iPhone 13, it has an aluminum frame with Gorilla Glass Victus+ front and back. Based on Samsung’s ads, the Galaxy S22 5G has an armor aluminum frame with tougher drop and scratch resistance. Moreover, this model is IP68 rated dust- and water-resistant.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Display</h2>



<p><strong>iPhone 13: </strong>The iPhone 13 has a 6.1-inch Super Retina XDR OLED panel with HDR10, and Dolby Vision support. Its display panel has a peak brightness of 1200 nits. As for display resolution, you get 1170 x 2532 image clarity, protected by a scratch-resistant ceramic glass with an oleophobic coating, wide color gamut, and Apple’s True Tone.</p>



<p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S22 5G: </strong>Not straying far, the Samsung Galaxy S22 also has a 6.1-inch size display, but with Dynamic AMOLED 2X, 120Hz refresh rate, HDR10+, and a peak brightness of 1300 nits. However, display clarity is where iPhone 13 wins over the Samsung Galaxy S22 5G, since the Galaxy S22 5G only has a 1080 x 2340 panel. Wondering what protects the Galaxy S22 5G’s display? It’s Corning Gorilla Glass Victus+ and the panel has an Always-on Display feature. Perfect for those who don’t like tapping their phones to check the time!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Platform</h2>



<p><strong>iPhone 13: </strong>The iPhone 13 runs iOS 15 out of the box, and is upgradable to the latest version of the iOS 15. It runs on Apple’s A15 Bionic chip which has six CPU cores with a 4-core Apple GPU. Storage-wise, the iPhone 13 is upgradeable up to 512 GB.</p>



<p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S22 5G:</strong> The Samsung Galaxy S22 5G is shipped out running Android 12 and is powered by Qualcomm SM8450 Snapdragon 8 Gen 1. Its CPU has eight cores and its graphics processor is Adreno 730, a brand you often see on Samsung smartphones. When it comes to storage, the Samsung Galaxy S22 5G is only up to 256 GB.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Camera</h2>



<p><strong>iPhone 13: </strong>Apple’s iPhone 13 has a dual-lens rear camera setup with the first lens being wide with 13 MP. The second lens is also 12 MP, but is ultrawide. Both lenses have their own LED dual-tone flashes and HDR photo and panorama. The highest video capture quality you can get from the iPhone 13 is 4K@60fps with Dolby Vision HDR support.</p>



<p>The front camera of the iPhone 13 has a single-lens setup, with 12 MP wide lens that is SL 3D supported. It has HDR and can take up to 4K@60fps videos.</p>



<p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S22 5G: </strong>Samsung’s contender for this buying guide has a triple-lens rear camera setup. The main is a wide lens that has 50 MP, the second is a telephoto lens that has 10 MP with 3x optical zoom, and the third lens is ultrawide and has 12 MP with Super Steady video. The rear camera setup has a LED flash, auto-HDR, and panorama. Samsung Galaxy S22 5G’s rear camera can take up to 8K@24fps videos with HDR10+ support.</p>



<p>Its front camera is a 10 MP wide lens with Dual Pixel PDAF, auto-HDR, and can take up to 4K@60fps videos.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Price</h2>



<p><strong>iPhone 13:</strong> Starts at $799 for the 128 GB model. It comes in Starlight, Midnight, Blue, Pink, Red, and Green.</p>



<p><strong>Samsung Galaxy S22 5G:</strong> Starts at $699.99 for the 128 GB with 8 GB RAM model. The Samsung Galaxy S22 5G comes in Phantom Black, White, Pink Gold, Green, Graphite, Sky Blue, Violet, and Cream.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What made you decide?</h2>



<p>Was it the camera? The body? Or the price? We know there are many factors in play, but for most people, the price is one of the biggest deciding factors. But if you’re a tech whiz who likes comparing every feature of the gadgets you’re planning to purchase, we hope this buying guide helped you pick the right smartphone for you!</p>



<p>If you need expert assistance when it comes to picking your new smartphone, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us and we’ll be happy to answer all your tech questions! Our friendly staff are available and will lead you to the smartphone that will serve your tech needs.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Best Streaming Services for 2022</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/the-best-streaming-services-for-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 16:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=19510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The phrase “going to the movies” has a new meaning thanks to online streaming services that a majority of us depended on when we’re not 100% sure about going out to see a movie in theaters. Since we can watch movies (even the newest ones) without going out of the house because of streaming services, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>The phrase “going to the movies” has a new meaning thanks to online streaming services that a majority of us depended on when we’re not 100% sure about going out to see a movie in theaters.</p>



<p>Since we can watch movies (even the newest ones) without going out of the house because of streaming services, it’s hard to imagine a weekend without them. So if you’re surfing the web looking for a new streaming service or another one to add to your list, you’re in the right place.</p>



<p>We jotted down the best streaming services for 2022 that we recommend:</p>



<ol><li>Netflix</li></ol>



<p>Netflix is known to have an impressive library of original movies, TV series, documentaries, and other types of consumable video content on its subscription-based platform. It’s probably the hottest streaming service right now because of its library alone and how accessible it is.</p>



<p>Outside of its original library, Netflix hosts classic movies and TV series people love to watch over and over, such as Friends, How I Met Your Mother, and other American series. It’s also home to an extensive list of hit series from South Korea and Japan.</p>



<p>When it comes to accessibility, you can count on Netflix to be available on any streaming device. You can use it on your smartphone, computer, Apple TV, smart TVs, and its library also supports streaming in 4K, HDR, and Dolby Atmos – for a price.</p>



<ol start="2"><li>Amazon Prime Video</li></ol>



<p>Amazon Prime can be bundled with a Prime Video subscription or as a standalone subscription Like Netflix, Amazon Prime Video has its own library of original movies and series. You can subscribe to Amazon Prime and have Prime Video bundled with it, or only pay for a Prime Video subscription to access its library of video content.</p>



<p>There are tons of international films, 4K HDR support, and rental feature. Since Prime Video has a set of exclusive titles, you have to pay extra to watch them on your streaming device. In addition, there are also channels you can watch using your Prime Video subscription, such as Paramount Plus and AMC Plus, among others.</p>



<ol start="3"><li>HBO Max</li></ol>



<p>HBO Max offers users an extensive library of iconic films and latest movie releases. You can subscribe to HBO Max ad-free or ad-supported, depending on your viewing preference.</p>



<p>Its library is constantly updated with the latest films from Warner Bros., new releases 45 days after their theatrical release, and a collection of content from classics such as Sesame Street, Adult Swim, etc.</p>



<p>However, despite its impressive library, it can’t stream in 4K HDR quality like Netflix and Amazon Prime Video. You’re limited to watching your favorites in 1080p, which isn’t all too bad if your display isn’t big or you stream on your smartphone.</p>



<ol start="4"><li>Disney Plus</li></ol>



<p>Streaming service Disney Plus is home to Marvel and Star Wars films. So if you’re a fan of both franchises, a Disney Plus subscription is highly recommended to ensure you get all the movies you need for binge-watching.</p>



<p>You can get Disney Plus as a standalone subscription or with ESPN+ and streaming service Hulu.</p>



<p>Aside from Marvel and Star Wars films in one place, you also get access to Disney’s classic movies! However, this may mean the content leans more towards general audiences. It’s excellent for family movie times, but not if you’re into mature titles.</p>



<p>As for stream quality, Disney Plus can stream 4K HDR to support high-resolution displays for the best viewing experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final thoughts</h2>



<p>When looking for streaming services, you should consider what titles you want to watch and check if specific providers have them in their libraries. Even though monthly subscriptions aren’t expensive, you can spend those dollars on better streaming services that actually have what you want to watch.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Apple Gadgets and Accessories to Get In 2022</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/top-5-apple-gadgets-and-accessories-to-get-in-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 17:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=19418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Apple is known for designing its products to support each other. This can be seen in how integrated their products are with each other, which manifests clearly in Apple’s native tracking application, Find My. Find My allows you to track all compatible Apple devices signed into your iCloud account and included in your Family Sharing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>Apple is known for designing its products to support each other. This can be seen in how integrated their products are with each other, which manifests clearly in Apple’s native tracking application, Find My. Find My allows you to track all compatible Apple devices signed into your iCloud account and included in your Family Sharing setup.</p>



<p>Another feature that takes advantage of Apple’s excellent cross-device integration is Universal Control. This feature lessens the time you take switching between your Apple devices. For example, you’re working on your MacBook, and you need a file from your iPad. You can simply drag and drop the file you need using your MacBook’s trackpad to navigate your iPad. What’s better is that Universal Control isn’t limited to two devices, but three.</p>



<p>With notable features making Apple gadgets easier to use, it’s time you find additional devices and accessories that’ll complete your Apple ecosystem. Here are five products we recommend:</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1. 16-inch M1 Max MacBook Pro</h2>



<p>The M1 Max is currently Apple’s most powerful processor, with 10-cores of CPU power and a GPU with up to 32-cores. The beefy Apple silicon is made even more powerful by 64GB of unified memory, making it a good MacBook for heavy video rendering and software development tasks.</p>



<p>The 16-inch MacBook Pro is built to be compatible with Apple’s latest integration feature, Universal Control, so that you can work between your other compatible devices without a problem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2. iPad Pro 12.9-inch</h2>



<p>Apple’s latest addition to their iPad Pro line are the 11- and 12.9-inch iPad Pro. Both come with up to 2TB of storage but differ in size, display quality, and battery capacity.</p>



<p>The iPad Pro 12.9-inch is powered by Apple’s M1 chip, which you’ll also find in their latest generation of MacBook Airs. The M1 chip has an 8-core CPU with 4 performance cores and 4 efficiency cores. In addition, it has an 8-core GPU with up to 16GB of RAM.</p>



<p>The 12-9-inch iPad Pro is fully compatible with Universal Control, so you can conveniently include it in your productivity arsenal and have no issues transferring what you need.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3. iPhone 13 Pro Max</h2>



<p>The iPhone 13 Pro Max is Apple’s fastest iPhone, with the A15 Bionic chip and the Pro camera system with Telephoto, Wide, and Ultra Wide modes. It’s also 5G capable, making it fast enough to connect to the internet and support your online tasks without an issue.</p>



<p>The iPhone 13 Pro Max is fully compatible with Universal Control, so working alongside your iPad and MacBook is made extremely convenient.</p>



<p>Lastly, it’s compatible with Apple’s MagSafe accessories, making charging up this smartphone a hassle-free experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">4. Apple Watch Series 7</h2>



<p>The Apple Watch Series 7 currently has the biggest display out of all Apple Watch models released in the previous years. This made it an even more competent smartwatch because users who aren’t fans of smaller displays benefit from its upgraded viewable area.</p>



<p>The retina display also has an always-on feature, so you don’t have to repeatedly tap on your watch to see the screen.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">5. MagSafe Duo Charger</h2>



<p>As Apple continues to develop MagSafe-supported devices, the MagSafe Duo Charger becomes even more relevant. It allows you to conveniently charge your compatible iPhone, Apple Watch, AirPods, and other Qi-certified devices without the trouble of plugging into a charging port.</p>



<p>With the MagSafe Duo Charger, you can just lay your device on top, and you’ll get the juice you need for your devices.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 3 iPad Pro Issues and How to Fix Them</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/top-3-ipad-pro-issues-and-how-to-fix-them/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 14:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=19276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you have an Apple iPad Pro and want to know how to fix the most common issues? You’re not alone. That’s why we prepared this guide to help you solve issues plaguing a lot of iPad Pro users. The Apple iPad Pro line is Apple’s best line of iPads to date. The first iPad [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>Do you have an Apple iPad Pro and want to know how to fix the most common issues? You’re not alone. That’s why we prepared this guide to help you solve issues plaguing a lot of iPad Pro users.</p>



<p>The Apple iPad Pro line is Apple’s best line of iPads to date. The first iPad was already impressive when it came out in 2010, taking the world by storm. Apple has outdone itself over the years, coming out with new iPads that make consumers jump in line to purchase the new, revolutionary features.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, each new feature has its issues and the iPad Pro is no different. While yes, it’s a highly capable device that can function like a small computer for basic computing tasks, it has its imperfections. We’re making it our duty to help you speed past the common issues you might encounter with your Apple iPad Pro.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1. The iPad Pro Shuts Down by Itself</h2>



<p>Your Apple iPad Pro shutting down without you doing anything to cause it to happen could be a result of a few different issues. It could be because the iPad is running too hot and is trying to save itself from damage by taking a break and shutting down. Your battery could also need replacing or it could be due to other iOS update bugs.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How to Fix It</h3>



<p><strong>Solution 1:</strong> If you run demanding applications for long periods of time, it’d be good if you can work somewhere that’s cold to help your iPad Pro regulate its own temperature without shutting down. This doesn’t mean you need to set the thermostat to 50 degrees Fahrenheit, just make sure your iPad is not sitting in direct sunlight for too long.</p>



<p>While the iPad Pro is capable of running demanding applications when compared to other iPads such as iPad Mini, Air, and iPad, it’s still not engineered to run heavy-load computing applications for long periods.</p>



<p><strong>Solution 2:</strong> Get your battery checked. The most probable cause of any battery-powered gadget shutting down by itself is a faulty battery. Fortunately, it’s not difficult to get Apple to replace your battery for a fee or without charge if your iPad Pro is under warranty. You can also contact your local repair shop to let them check your battery for signs of deterioration and have them replace it for you.</p>



<p><strong>Solution 3:</strong> Keep your iPadOS up to date. Apple keeps an eye on common software issues and regularly sends software updates for customers. Make sure your iPad is up-to-date, running the newest software and you should have fewer difficulties. If the problem persists, you’ll have to reach out to Apple’s support lines to get personal assistance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2. Your iPad Pro Can’t Connect to Wi-Fi Networks</h2>



<p>If your iPad Pro can’t connect to Wi-Fi networks at home, in your office, or at co-working spaces, the problem may be with the device itself and not different routers. If you find yourself having trouble connecting to Wi-Fi networks anywhere you go, it’s a sign to get your device checked by Apple or your local iPad repair service provider.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Get It Fixed</h3>



<p>Going to the experts is the best solution, especially if your Wi-Fi settings aren’t grayed out and can detect networks you can’t connect to. This can mean the issue lies with the iPad Pro’s components, and getting it checked out by professionals would definitely answer your most pressing Wi-Fi questions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3. The iPad Pro Is Not Charging</h2>



<p>Do you find yourself plugging your lightning cable in and out before you hear the distinctive Apple charging sound? Or does your iPad Pro take ages to get fully charged? These two things can be the effect of many issues with both your iPad Pro and charger.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Fix</h3>



<p><strong>Solution 1:</strong> The first step in any troubleshooting is isolating the problem. First, try to use different chargers on your iPad Pro. If it does not work, it’s your iPad Pro that has an issue. If you’ve tried multiple chargers and they work, it’s the cable you usually charge with.</p>



<p><strong>Solution 2:</strong> Your battery is dying. Literally. The only way to fix a dying battery is to get it replaced with a fresh one. If your iPad Pro is still under warranty, you can get your battery replaced for less at Apple. If not, it might be cheaper to get your local iPad repair shop to replace your battery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Final Thoughts</h2>



<p>Alas, you’ve reached the end of our short but insightful guide. We hope this helped you and that you can now identify any issues with your iPad Pro. Remember that while DIY projects are fun, it’s best to take your iPad Pro to your local repair shop and have the experts fix the issue.</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holiday Shopping: Computer Edition</title>
		<link>https://computerrepairdoctor.com/holiday-shopping-computer-edition/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott D.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://computerrepairdoctor.com/?p=19068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every year, we get thinner, more powerful, and of course, more expensive computers. Manufacturers are racing to be the first in new designs and capabilities so they can capture the hearts of consumers. Whether you use a computer for office-purpose or gaming &#8212; there is a perfect computer out there for you. Brands have been [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner">
<p>Every year, we get thinner, more powerful, and of course, more expensive computers. Manufacturers are racing to be the first in new designs and capabilities so they can capture the hearts of consumers. Whether you use a computer for office-purpose or gaming &#8212; there is a perfect computer out there for you.</p>



<p>Brands have been in this game for so long, that they already know what we want and need.</p>



<p>If you’re in the market for your next computer, the holiday season is the perfect time to score the best deals on your next machine. Holiday shopping isn’t all about small gifts now &#8212; it’s about time we treat ourselves (or our loved ones) to a new shiny gadget.</p>



<p>Don’t worry, we’re not going to bombard you with sponsored brands and models of computers that came out this year. In this article, we’ll list the best computers based on what type of user you are. A gamer, a casual user, or a professional? We have a computer recommendation for you.</p>



<p>Ready to score your next computer? Read below and take your pick:</p>



<ol><li><strong>MacBook Air</strong></li></ol>



<p>The first one in Apple’s line of computers to run without Intel, the MacBook Air M1 hits the sweet spot from every possible angle. From its known portability because of how light it is compared to the MacBook Pro and non-Apple computers, it’s also one of Apple’s most popular laptop models.</p>



<p>Compared to other Macs, the Macbook Air is not expensive. It’s light, has many features, and is easy to use. You’ll see students use MacBook Airs often because they can take it anywhere without breaking their backs and banks.</p>



<p>Of course, we know you’d love to know the techy stuff about the Air M1. <a href="https://support.apple.com/kb/SP825?locale=en_PH">Click here</a> for all the technical specifications you could want.</p>



<p>Looking to buy the MacBook Air M1? Weigh your needs first. What will you be using it for? Do you do photo and video editing often, are you planning to use it for gaming?&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you answered those two questions with a yes, then you’re better off with a MacBook Pro or a Windows gaming laptop since both can better handle those tasks.&nbsp;</p>



<ol start="2"><li><strong>ASUS ROG Zephyrus G15</strong></li></ol>



<p>Interested in a computer for gaming? Let’s look at the computer that’s best capable of running the latest titles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A good example of a modern title is Ubisoft’s action-adventure first-person shooter, Far Cry 6. It’s a hardware-demanding game and, as a gamer, I know you’d want nothing but the smoothest gaming experience. Especially with a title that’s as immersive as Far Cry 6.</p>



<p>That’s why ASUS’ ROG Zephyrus G15 would be the perfect computer option for you.</p>



<p>Its base model is powered by the RTX 3050 GPU (exclusive to laptops) with the Ryzen 9 5900HS the processor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With a base processing speed of 3.1 GHz, you’ll have enough juice to launch your games faster and keep up with fast-paced titles like Riot Games’ first-person shooter Valorant.</p>



<p>Of course, a beefy GPU and a fast processor are nothing without a top-of-the-line display panel. With the Zephyrus G15, you get a 15.6-inch 1440p display.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you play a lot of first-person games, you’ll be satisfied with the display’s 165Hz refresh rate and 3ms response time.</p>



<p>Worried about colors and sync? The display panel is IPS and AMD FreeSync-enabled. No dead colors and screen-tearing. Only the best gaming experience possible.</p>



<p>Is this laptop only for gaming? No, it can be used for a wide variety of tasks.</p>



<p>It’s powerful enough to run hardware-demanding software used in photo and video editing, so you can’t go wrong with the Zephyrus G15.</p>



<ol start="3"><li><strong>MacBook Pro</strong></li></ol>



<p>Are we talking high-end photo and video editing? We can’t forget 2021’s MacBook Pro.</p>



<p>Apple’s October event introduced the remodeled MacBook Pro. The 2021 line added the 13-inch Pros to the MacBooks family.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The base model, MacBook Pro 13”, still has the M1 chip from the Air M1. The processor revamps start when you look at the 14” and 16” models. They’re powered by the upgraded M1 Pro and M1 Max chips, which sports up to 10 cores of processing power.</p>



<p>When it comes to graphics, the new Apple chips boast up to 32 cores of display processing.</p>



<p>Since storage is a big factor for photo and video editors, we’d like to highlight that the maximum configurable storage for these new MacBook Pros goes up to 8TB. Depending on the usual size of your work, this might be enough. If not, an external storage drive is always an option.</p>



<p>Despite the upgrades on hardware, the new MacBook Pros remain light. The base model weighs 1.4kg. The heaviest is the 16” model, which weighs 2.1kg.</p>



<ol start="4"><li><strong>Dell XPS 13 2-in-1</strong></li></ol>



<p>If there’s anything I’ve learned in technology, it’s that brands will find a way to combine things that make consumers happy.</p>



<p>Remember when tablets became popular? Today some of them are powerful enough to function like computers, but not so much that they can replace computers.</p>



<p>That’s how 2-in-1s came to be. Just a few years back we couldn’t imagine folding a laptop backwards without breaking it. Today, laptop screens can be rotated 180 degrees.</p>



<p>If you’re into the quirky features 2-in-1s have, Dell XPS 13 2-in-1 is a great pick. It’s powered by an 11th Generation Intel Core i5 CPU and an Intel Iris Xe GPU. The processor is good enough to handle day-to-day office tasks and browsing, but when you want to play modern titles using this 2-in-1, you won’t have an ideal gaming experience.</p>



<p>When it comes to the XPS 13’s display, you get a 13.4-inch touch panel. Unlike traditional laptops, its display can be used in a variety of ways. Turn and spin (carefully) to your comfort and you can rely on it to keep working when you do so.</p>



<p>Storage-wise, it has a PCIe NVMe SSD. SSDs are known to be faster than HDDs by a mile. And being in a PCIe lane with NVMe further shoots this convertible laptop’s storage speed ahead of HDDs.</p>



<p>Weight is a big factor for laptop fans. To guide you, this one weighs 1.32kg. A pretty common weight for modern Windows laptops.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Takeaways</strong></h2>



<p>Depending on what you want a laptop for, you’ll be better off with a MacBook or a Dell laptop. It all really depends on what you’re planning to use the laptop for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’re not the best when it comes to computers, sales representatives at computer stores will be more than glad to assist you with finding the best computer for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just tell them what you intend to use the computer you’re looking for and they’ll be ready with suggestions.</p>



<p>Whatever your choice ends up being, we wish you happy holiday shopping!</p>
</div></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
